Kevin Lawler

kevinrlawler@gmail.com
847-226-6734
www.kevinrlawler.com
https://www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-lawler
https://github.com/klawgolfer7

Front-End Developer with experience working in the tech world within multiple capacities. Worked directly with CTOs and Lead Developers. Great enthusiasm and passion for exploration of new technologies. Focused on using all resources to produce great web and mobile responsive applications.

Technical Skills:

- HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap
- JavaScript, React.js, Angular.js, AJAX, node.js, jQuery, Express.js, Webpack, NPM package control
- SQL, MySQL, Firebase, MongoDB
- Git version control
- Browser Dev tools
- Sublime text editor

Education:

Rutgers Coding Bootcamp

An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned consisted of HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React.js, Bootstrap, AngularJS, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express.js, Handlebars.js, & jQuery. November 2016 – May 2017

New York Code and Design Academy

Front End 101 April – June 2016 Web Development 100 January – March 2016

University of Illinois

B.S. Sports Marketing, Minor in Business and Computer Science

Online Programs:

W3schools: JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS **Codecademy:** HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Git, Command Line

Code School: CSS, jQuery

Udemy: Weird Parts of Javascript.

Projects:

Cancer Alliance 2017

https://cancer-alliance.herokuapp.com/#/?_k=f9jkgr https://github.com/klawgolfer7/gitgirls2

- Web application that allows cancer patients to come together for support, find articles about their cancer, and provide and receive Doctor recommendations.
- Utilized React.js, webpack, Babel and Bootstrap on the front-end and MongoDB, Node.js, Cheerio.js and Express.js on the server side.

Limelight 2017

https://github.com/klawgolfer7/movie-project

- Allows users to enter the name of an actor and the app will return biographical and career information on the selected actor, as well as the results of a YouTube search of his/her various movies' trailers
- Used IMDB and YouTube API's to make calls from users input
- JavaScript, Angular.js jQuery, Bootstrap

Connect 4, Front End Developer

https://github.com/klawgolfer7/connect4

- Used JavaScript, AngularJS, CSS3, and Bootstrap for animation
- Developed mobile responsive features with Bootstrap
- Coded custom Directives and Functions
- Created Mock-up for project

Surprise

https://github.com/klawgolfer7/Surprise

2017

2016

- Allows users to sign up for Bar and Restaurant promotions
- Business owners can reach out to users to offer limited time event's
- Users receive events based on either their location or by actively requesting them.

Burger Menu 2017

https://github.com/klawgolfer7/Burger-Choices

- Menu style application that logs user's input into MySQL
- Uses Sequelize to help setup the database

Train Schedule 2017

https://github.com/klawgolfer7/train-schedule

- Train schedule application that incorporates Firebase to host arrival and departure data
- Moment.js utilized to find the exact time user's next available train would come

Wedding Website, Front End Developer

2016

https://klawgolfer7.github.io/One-Page-Wedding-Website/

- Used JavaScript, jQuery, CSS3, and Stellar.JS for animation
- Developed mobile responsive features with Bootstrap
- Developed features such as alerts, toggles, and class adds
- Created a wireframe and outlined link structure
- Changed fonts by using Google font API
- Developed the entire site with sublime text editor
- Committed all debugging through pushes with Git

Relevant Work Experience:

Randstad Technologies/Modis Technical Recruiter/Account Manager

New York, NY

June 2015 – June 2017

- Specialized in client and account management and in recruiting all types of Software Engineers in the Greater New York City area from start-ups to large Fortune 500 companies by using social media for recruitment
- Worked directly with developers and engineers by vetting and testing them prior to submitting to clients
- Worked with CTO's, CIO's, Director of Technologies on a day to day basis to understand their needs and consult with them on the direction of the Marketplace

Additional Work Experience:

Nolan Transportation Group

Chicago, IL

National Accounts Manager

May 2014-June 2015

- Evaluated customers' transportation requirements and proposed and managed transportation solutions
- Expanded company's client base by bringing in 30 new clients within the first 9 months of employment.

Groupon Inc. Chicago, IL

Senior Account Executive

January 2013-April 2014

- Built a book of business from \$500,000 to \$1.5 million
- Generated between \$90,000-\$150,000 a month in Gross Profit for all 14 months on the Washington D.C. market

• Grew book of business by closing 21% of monthly quota as new business features

Account Executive

- Accelerated Charleston into a top 40 market at Groupon by hitting my monthly goal 10 months in a row
- Facilitated the launch of Charleston as a new market by closing 40 contracts in 2 months over the phone
- Built a book of business from \$0 to \$550,000 in my tenure on the Charleston market
- Involved in all aspects of feature, from getting contract signed, to editorial changes and client services.